myvolusiaschools.org 2019-08-29

# Privacy Statement | Volusia County Schools

This statement encompasses all World Wide Web pages operating under [https://www.vcsedu.org](https://www.vcsedu.org/) (the "Website") and controlled by The School District of Volusia County (the "District"), and is intended to define the privacy of visitor information gathered and disseminated within them.

## Introduction

The District respects the importance of responsibly using information collected on the Website. Personally Identifiable Information about visitors is not collected unless they agree to make such information available to us. There is no legal requirement for visitors to provide any personally identifiable information on the Website. Visitors may contact the office, department or individual requesting information by phone, email or in writing. However, some of the District's services and products may not be available to these visitors without providing Personally Identifiable Information.

## Non-Personally Identifiable Information

The District collects anonymous web traffic data via tools such as Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager to generate summary statistics to help guide design considerations, determine successful website segments, and determine areas we can improve the Website's functionality. In some instances, the District may be compelled by existing laws of the United States or other applicable local, state and federal laws, and applicable policies, rules and guidelines of the District, including those defined herein, to release non-personally identifiable information gathered from our web servers to law enforcement.

For privacy information related to how Google safeguards data contained in its analytics and measurement platforms (of which both Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager are a part), please refer to Google's [Safeguarding Your Data](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en) page.

## Personally Identifiable Information

All personal information submitted to the District via web forms is considered strictly confidential, unless stated otherwise. This information may be shared between offices, departments, groups or individuals within the District, as needed or required, and as governed by the District's data standards and information security policies. The District will not release personal information to third parties except as required by law.

## Visitor Interaction

The District allows interaction with its employees via email and forms in online and PDF formats. Any information disclosed within these mediums is considered public information under the [State of Florida's public records law](http://myfloridalegal.com/pages.nsf/Main/DC0B20B7DC22B7418525791B006A54E4) (commonly known as the Sunshine Law). Visitors should exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in them.

## Information Security

The District will take reasonable technical and organizational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of personal information and will not provide, rent or sell personal information to third parties for marketing programs or any other purpose.

The District does not disclose Personally Identifiable Information, whether said information is identifiable explicitly or implicitly, except in the following cases:

  * To employees, contractors and affiliated organizations of the District when necessary to conduct business, and only upon their agreement to not subsequently disclose the information.
  * When required to do so by law.
  * When the District believes in good faith disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect its property, its rights, third parties and the public well-being.

If you have supplied the District with your email address, the District may choose to occasionally email you news, notices or other matters of interest. Emails sent in this way will include opt-out options within them.

## Student and Child Privacy

### Compliance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA)

The District complies with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which restricts the release of educational records. For more details on FERPA please visit the U.S. Department of Education's [FERPA website](https://www2.ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/ferpa/index.html).

### Compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)

The District complies with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), which requires parental consent be obtained before individuals under the age of 13 can submit any personal information via the District's website or tools available on it. For more details on COPPA please visit the Federal Trade Commission's [Children's Privacy website](https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/privacy-and-security/children%27s-privacy).
